On today's video, we are going to make a
Whopper
ice cream, which is
kind of close to Maltesas. So, nice and
easy. Let's get straight on it.
[Music]
The North American version of this. They
are similar, but they're not the same.
These are much lighter. These are a bit
denser. There's a much stronger malt
flavor for Whoppers than there are for
Maltesers. And the chocolate is
infinitely different. As you'd expect,
the chocolate from Maltesas is a
European style chocolate. So much nicer
than the turd that this is covered in.
But I prefer Whoppers over Maltesas. My
wife prefers Maltesers over Whoppers.
But today, as I'm the one making it,
it's Whoppers. Now, we can't actually do
anything with these in ice cream, per
se. We can just drop them in, but they
do go quite hard. We can't take the
chocolate off. It's just too
timeconuming. And even if you could, the
stuff inside just dissipates in liquid.
So, as the moisture or water from your
ice cream seeps in, it just kind of
melts down into nothing. Be exactly the
same for these. But what we can do is
take that flavor. So, we're going to use
dry malt extract. Uh it's super easy to
buy from any kind of brewing shop,
Amazon, anything like that. Easy. Uh if
you're in Europe, then just use malt
extract, liquid malt. You can buy that
in pretty much any supermarket. Uh it's
super easy. So, let's just get on and
make it. What are we going to need for
this recipe? You are going to need 250 g
of whole milk, 500 g of heavy cream. You
can either use three large egg yolks or
1.2 g of stabilizer,
150 g of sugar, and we're going to add
in 5 g of vanilla extract, 50 g of our
malt powder, and a pinch of salt. So,
cup measurements on the screen just then
for all of you. Recipe in the
description. Let's get everything
weighed out. I don't know what this is
all about.
[Music]
The dry malt extract been in there for
over a year. You get these little hard
lumps. It's actually not a problem
because they'll just dissipate as we
warm this up. So, don't kind of stress
about it.
You can see, you probably can't see to
be fair. There's some really big ass
lumps in there. it just
breaks apart. But malt is just another
type of sugar. Um, it was actually sold
as a health food uh, you know, back in
the 50s, maybe even the 60s as well. I
love malt flavor. So, with that said,
everything is going in our pan. There's
our milk,
our cream. I want all of that in there.
our sugar with our
malt powder, malt extract. If you want
to use like molted milk powder, which I
know is very popular in the US, you
absolutely can use that. You would
probably just sub it one to one for the
malt powder. It won't be as strong a
flavor. That is it. This is going to go
on the heat. We've used a stabilizer in
this rather than egg yolks. So, if
you're using egg yolks, put them all in
now and heat it up to 75 C, which is
this in Fahrenheit. As we're using a
stabilizer,
I need to heat this up to 85 C, which is
this in Fahrenheit. Then, we're going to
get it off the heat. 85 C. Always seems
like for those people that are just
starting on ice cream and you're heating
up a base cuz you're using a stabilizer
or using obviously egg yolks, always
seems like you're getting quite high.
And there's a lot of people that boil
dairy to make ice cream. Uh it's a it's
a very common practice in Asia. Um
honestly, I don't know why because it
just it bitters the taste of the dairy.
Dairy denatures from 80 to 85 C. Um so
there's absolutely no need to to boil
it. And denaturing just means the how
the proteins interact changes. So, I'll
go into more detail on on this subject
in another video, but it just means that
you can create a better mouth feel by
heating up to the 8085 degree range. You
can do that with egg yolks, too. Just be
careful. We got a glorious silky smooth
molted milk base. And I'm just going to
wait for this to cool down for 5 or 10
minutes. And then I'm going to drop in
my vanilla extract. You can use between
5 and 10 gram. So, one to two teaspoons
of this. In we go.
One, two. I I went with two. Floaty
expense. That's now going to go in the
refrigerator
for at least 4 hours. What time is it
now? It's 10:00 in the morning, and I've
just realized I have my sunglasses on my
head the entire time so far. So, five
points if you spotted it. Um, 10:00 now.
I'm going to put this in for at least 4
hours, get this chilled down to
refrigerator temperature, and then I'll
get churning.
So, after completely chilling down in
the refrigerator, I'm going to take it
out and get it mixed back up. There's
quite a heavy skin on top, but it tastes
delicious. Then, it's time to pour into
our pre- chilled ice cream machine. If
you're going to use an inch creamy, then
put it straight in. Put it in the
freezer. Whilst it's churning, we're
going to take our chocolate. This is a
55% chocolate from Belcalade, which
actually tastes disgusting, but it works
in this recipe as well. We're going to
add in 1 and 1/2 teaspoon of deodorized
coconut oil. This is refined coconut
oil. and heat it up in stages until it
becomes super nice and liquid. Then
we're going to start adding it into our
ice cream as a stretchyella right at the
end of the churn before finally dishing
it up into our containers. We had good
overrun on this. So, let's get this
dished up and see what the whole thing
looks like. Here we go out the freezer.
It's been in there overnight and it's
got a really good dishing te texture and
consistency. Scooped really nicely. It
looks delicious. Super creamy. Looking
forward to this. Let's go. There we go.
Our Whopper ice cream. Just to
top that off. One on top. One for me.
The North American version of a malt
tea. Let's see what this result is like.
It's delicious. That malt flavor really
punches through at the start. And I find
that a lot of molted ice creams just
aren't strong enough in flavor. This one
is is perfect. It's really It's not
overpoweringly strong, but it's strong
enough to to make that flavor come
through really early. The chocolate
shards, the stretchyella style chocolate
is beautiful.
Lovely texture, perfect scooping
consistency as well. You saw every time
I take an ice cream out of the freezer,
they don't sit here for hours on end
whilst they get soft enough to scoop. I
like my ice creams to be scooped
straight out of the freezer. So, all my
recipes are adjusted to do that. And
yeah, this is delicious. I'm going to
eat this whole thing. It is
half 9 in the morning. Don't forget to
like and subscribe. See you next week.
[Music]